drew sympathy from spectators and strengthen the resolve of Christian communities.
Christianity presented a challenge to the usual Roman methods of social control. Not only had
their so-called God died, but he had returned from the dead and promised that Christians too would
rise again. This meant the threat of death, usually such an effective tool for discipline,
had lost its sting. For the average Roman citizen, this was unthinkable. The idea of life after death
was inconceivable except for the greatest empress and warriors. The threat of death usually held
because this life was the only possible existence for Romans, but these Christians confidently believed
in a resurrected life after death. In fact, by the end of the second century, their courage in the
face of death was one of their most noted qualities by Roman authors. And remember where Pliny is?
Bethynia Pontus. This was where Christians had received a letter in the previous generation.