But through all his interrogations, all he discovered was that Christians were having a meal,
which they called a Thanksgiving meal, which also involved a ritual with bread and wine,
which they called the body and the blood of Jesus. So no children hiding in the bread?
Not at all. In fact, Christians were known to rescue and raise abandoned Roman babies,
as they rejected the Roman practice of killing or abandoning unwanted children.
The way Christians lived flowed from what they were taught in their meetings.
They went around talking about a loving God who loved the world and demanded love between people,
even between enemies. In their meetings, they were taught to reject magic and violence,
and they were known for caring for the sick, as well as their very restrained,
sexual ethic. All this was highly counter-cultural in Roman society. Roman authors,
like the philosopher Galen and the satirist Lucian, both pitted and admired Christians for how they
really lived out these ideals. All this made Christians seem like a scary and a mysterious community,